e
hey we have o' so I will call the March
meeting of the historic Architectural
Review Board to order uh just by way of
brief introduction uh the harb is a
recommending board um so the actions
that are taken here this evening will
then be uh moved on to city council who
will ultimately um act on on harb's
recommendation and
um that will likely be at the March 11th
um 202 25 meeting uh each member of the
uh committee is uh is utilizes the
Secretary of the Interior standards in
terms of review of the projects and um
and we're Bound by those guidelines and
reviewing what's before us in terms of a
process we'd ask the applicant to come
up to the table um have Suzanne um read
or summarize her review of the project
um have any questions um from the board
and then open it up if there's any
public that has questions so the first
item on the agenda is 307 South Lim
Street
Stephen uh Evan galista owner
Evangelista I'm sorry thank you and it's
replacement of a multi-light picture
window with aluminum storefront window
on the facade of a commercial building
so yeah that way you can use why don't
you the the table and then if you please
make sure you turn your mic on and I'll
remind the board members too to use your
mics
please yep you hear me thank you
yep soan can you can you please read
your replace
um a a metal frame picture window with
SM panes with a um a a large aluminum
storefront window my review is
appropriate the existing multi-light
picture window was installed in 1979
when the building was used by a metal
working business or a tin shop that
advertised early American lighting
reproductions while relating to the tin
shop business and its Colonial theme
picture window does not relate to the
agent style of this utilitarian building
which was built about 19 uh 25 as a
garage or auto repair shop the proposed
storefront window will be an appropriate
modern alteration that is more in
keeping with the building form and stop
and this review references standards
number 29 and
10 thank you Suzanne do you have
anything you'd like to add to the by by
way of explanation or no you covered
well it's just a existing window that
has some uh there's previous water
damage around the window that that's
since been repaired so there's kind of
rust on the interior of it that you can
kind of see from the outside so um
that's kind of the reason for the
replacement
okay thank you are there any questions
or comments from the
board just the one comment um Suzanne
this is really not so much about the
proposed window but about the mention of
a change in signage yeah will that have
to come before I spoke to Mr Evangelista
he does not because he's it's the
business doesn't have a lot of walk-in
customers he's just using his Warehouse
he doesn't have any signage plan to be
mounted on the exterior which you would
review if he just has decals of
something on the inside window or door
that would not be reviewed okay you want
to mount a sign on the wall or on the
Brack that would have to come back okay
that's good to know for the future yeah
we don't have any plans of that but
you're saying if we do want to do
something out in the future that's kind
of revisit that okay and you would do it
through zoning and then also through the
okay I could have know okay thank
you any other questions from the
board no it seems rather straightforward
uh Suzanne thank you very much for your
um uh for your review uh Mr chairman I
recommend that city council hold on one
I'm sorry are there are there any
comments from the public oh yes right
yeah okay
great Mr chairman I recommend the city
council approve a certificate of
appropriateness for the proposed
alteration at 307 South Lime Street to
replace an existing multi-light picture
window on the facade of a commercial
building with a quer aluminum storefront
window to feature a dark Bronze finish
per the submitted proposal this work
meets the Secretary of interior
standards number 29 and 10 I will make
one note on that I know it says dark
bronze but they kind of came in and gave
us the quote to match existing bronze
color it it'll be black okay if that's
okay yeah I just wanted to make note of
that so there's no questions we also I
can also put up the photo should I do
that on the screen I think we we all
here yes if we had yeah I reviewed it
yeah that's fine okay so we have a
motion is there a
second
okay discussion on the motion I guess
we'll clarify in terms of the the Finish
U we don't really comment on color but
this would be finished so right so inic
to Intrinsic to it so okay the black
finish you could
paint okay you have that that
clarification and then any other any
other
discussion
questions none others in favor I I
oppos thank you thank you
thank
you all right administrative approvals
uh we're in your packet we've got 16
South Lim Street installation of new
rubber roofing on a flat
roof surprised that one even falls under
our review can you see the roof
yeah
okay okay 229 Church Street in kind
replacement of asphalt roof shingles 220
Howard Avenue in kind replacement of
asphalt roof shingles 429 Church Street
in kind replacement of Cedar Shake roof
and cedar siding that's great 208 North
conquer Street uh inlike kind
replacement of steel door with sidel
with recessed
entryway and 107 Howard Avenue
replacement of a one over one wooden
windows on the facade following
violation notice after vinyl sash was
installed without a permit so that's
good to see too are there any questions
on the administrative
approvals okay hearing none those will
be part of the
record uh minutes from December 3D were
there any questions or Corrections on
those move the minutes be accepted as
presented okay we have a a motion is
there a
second okay all those in favor please
say I
I thank you other business election of
officers election of chair and vice
chair for
2025 there wouldn't be any harm in
postponing that we'd have the full group
here in case somebody was feeling
excited yeah right
what postpone okay all right all right
so we'll postpone that and then
assignment of a board member to take
part in the March
11th uh city council meeting which I
don't think we need to worry about
right so the only other item under other
business I we hadn't been together for a
while so it hasn't been front of my um
thoughts but we do need to find the
broker so just to discuss that in the
public meeting that the board is down
the real estate uh professional they do
need to be a broker so um if the if the
folks here can think of other folks that
uh would have property in the city
right they just have
to oh that's good to know okay yeah and
uh I made a recommendation just a
connection to Suzanne uh a couple of
months ago and I think that that
conversation is ongoing so okay
hopefully we'll so we have one Prospect
yep okay that seemed pretty excited
about it they don't live in Lancaster
but they are a broker and they've been
very interested in historic preservation
in general the topic uh for quite some
time so
okay all right thank you for that does
anybody else have any other
business then we will will adjourn at
608 which may be one of
our best ones all right thanks everybody
thank you thank you